Siarhei Khilko

Santa Clara, CA
<u>siarhei.khilko@gmail.com</u>
<u>github.com/skhilko</u>

Objective

Challenging position with a creative work environment where I can further my career as a front-end web developer, and utilize technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript to create intuitive, elegant, and cutting-edge user experiences.

Skills

Languages

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS

Prior Experience

- Java
- SQL

Technologies

- Client-side MV* frameworks
- DOM API
- REST
- Responsive design
- CSS frameworks & preprocessors
- Template engines
- Linux

Personal Projects

- Akno (http://skhilko.github.io/akno/) A UI widget for creating fast and beautiful modal dialogs.
- <u>StickyHeaders (http://skhilko.github.io/StickyHeaders/)</u> A JS library which enables sticky section headers in a scrollable list view.

Work Experience

Software Engineer

Nov 2010 - Present

Exadel, Inc.

Front-end Technical Lead at Sears Holdings Corporation - Contractor (Redwood City, CA)

- Redesigned front-end architecture of Sears Product Information Network application using client-side MVC approach with JavaScriptMVC on the client and Jersey REST Web Services in Java on the server-side. Lead development efforts to apply new design principles.
- Created and managed build process for front-end codebase to ease the development (automatic recompilation, tests, documentation) and maximize performance in production (assets optimization, cache control).

 Designed and maintained a library of rich UI components including a data grid, autocomplete, combobox, dialog, etc.

Software Engineer

Jun 2009 - Nov 2010

Exadel, Inc.

Front-end Team Lead at Sears Holdings Corporation - Offshore Team (Minsk, Belarus)

- Led a team of 5 engineers in end-to-end web application development.
- Implemented features for Sears Marketplace Seller Portal using a proprietary Java MVC framework, JSP, jQuery and jQuery UI.
- Contributed to Sears MVC framework.

Software Engineer

Feb 2008 - May 2009

EPAM Systems

Software Engineer at SupplyOn AG - Offshore Team (Minsk, Belarus)

- Developed a library of rich UI components for JSF using GWT, Richfaces and JavaScript.
- Implemented various areas of a sourcing management portal using <u>SAP NetWeaver</u> (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SAP NetWeaver) technology stack, including the presentation layer with JSF, business logic and persistence with EJB.

Software Engineer

Jan 2004 – Jan 2008

Autopromservice, Belarus

- Developed an appointment scheduling web application for a service center using the Apache Struts MVC framework and JDBC.
- Deployed <u>1C:Enterprise Platform (http://1c-dn.com/1c_enterprise/what_is_1c_enterprise/)</u>.
 Subsequently developed business and reporting modules for day-to-day operational needs of an accounting department, a warehouse and a service center.

Education

Master in Computer Science

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics, 2005

Associate in Electronics Engineering Technology

Minsk State Higher College of Radio Engineering, 2002

Certifications

Sun Certified Programmer for the Java Platform, Standard Edition 6 (2008)